Address: Connecticut, USA

 $(\bowtie)$ 

mchendrickson@wpi.edu

## About me

My name is Matthew Hendrickson, I am currently an upperclassman at Worcester Polytechnic Institute focusing on a double major in their Computer Science/Interactive Media and Game Design program. On the side, I prototype and develop software in Java and the Unity Engine for various purposes, most of them revolving around Game Design. I have also worked in IT and as a Peer Tutor for Quinnipiac University, which I have since transferred from.

## **Skills**

- **Customer Service**
- Agile Methodology
- CPR and First Aid
- Object-Oriented Design
- Project Managment
- Technical Support

### **Programming Languages**

- Java 🕌
- Python 🤔
- p5.js **p5**\*
- Javascript 🔢

## Software

- Jetbrains Suite 🛄
- Blender 7



- Adobe Photoshop Ps
- Git/GitHub



- Unity Engine
- Microsoft Office

## **Personal Work**



Imperius is an easy-to-learn, hard-to-master space RTS game that leverages creativity to achieve victory. Construct powerful fleets, plan ahead, and utilize powerful abilities across 6 campaign missions, featuring unique environments and a variety of foes.

Imperius will be availible on the Steam store the Summer of 2023. It will be brought to completion as my Major Qualifying Project for my double major at WPI.

# Matthew Hendrickson

Software Engineer/Game Designer



## **Education**

2021 - 2023	Worcester Polytechnic Institute ♀ Worcester, MA
GPA: 4.00	Computer Science
	interactive Media & Game reclinology
2019 - 2021	Quinnipiac University O Hamden, CT
CD4 2 00	Computer Science Sachelor of Arts
GPA: 3.98	Game Design & Development   Bachelor of Arts
2015 - 2019	Pomperaug Regional High School ♀ Southbury, CT
GPA: 3.62	High Honors

## **Experience**

Junior Backend Developer 05.2022 - 07/2022 ♀ Worcester, MA WPI/ASSISTments | new.assistments.org

Description: An IQP (Interactive Qualifying Project) for course credit at WPI using SQL and Python to add features to the award winning ASSISTments learning software.

Project Manager 03.2022 - 05.2022 ♥ Worcester, MA WPI/Brigham & Women's Hospital | www.brighamandwomens.org

Description: WPI's CS3733 Software Engineering D22 class in collaboration with Brigham & Women's Hospital. Applying the agile development methodologies and software design patterns in Java to create a medical equipment tracking and workflow application to demo features to the hospital representatives that they may consider implementing.

Tech Support Assistant Supervisor 08.2020 - 08.2021 ♀ Hamden, CT Quinnipiac University | www.qu.edu/info-for/information-technology-services

Description: Providing comprehensive support and problem resolution to users concerning both personal and university software and hardware, maintaining and upgrading university technology.

**Peer Tutor** 01.2021 - 08.2021 **♀** Hamden, CT

Quinnipiac University | www.qu.edu/student-life/support-services/

**Description:** Tutoring students in various programming-related topics in the languages JavaScript, C#, and Java for the Quinnipiac Learning Commons.

**Information Technologist** 06.2017 - Present ♀ Southbury, CT Practical Data Solutions | www.pds-online.com

**Description:** Hands-on experience through upgrading systems, technical support, repairing broken computers, installing server operating systems, and beta testing software.